<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 13:33:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 07:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20653</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most out of them. Let’s get started!<br />
<span id="more-20653"></span></p>
<p>The first stats are often referred to collectively as KPI’s, or key performance indicators. Most companies use one or several of these statistics to evaluate their store’s overall performance compared to industry standards or past store performance.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Dashboard</h2>
<p>The first chart you’ll see when you open your shop is your dashboard. Below we explain how each stat is calculated, what it tells you about your shop, and how the number can be skewed.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20664" alt="Bo" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Bo.gif" width="972" height="497" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Sales</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all order totals)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This number is pretty straightforward &#8211; it shows you how much money your shop is making. Hopefully, you’ll see an upward trend: in other words, your shop is making more money this month then it did the previous month. An upward trend shows your shop is growing and converting more customers, while a downward trend shows that customers are not purchasing as much or as often.</p>
<p>However, merchants generally see increases and decreases from month to month. The holiday sales season is a perfect example: strong holiday sales are often followed by a high number of returns.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Orders</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Number of orders received)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to know the number of orders that your store receives, because it indicates the number of customers you are successfully converting. Ideally, you’d like to see an upward trend here, too. However, don’t be surprised if you find that this number dips during slower months. You can easily compare each month’s performance against numbers from the previous year to continually evaluate your store’s growth.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Cart Value</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sales / Orders)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Average cart value indicates the average amount that a customer spends on each visit to your site. <span style="text-decoration: underline">Cross-selling and upselling features have proven to effectively increase this number</span>. However, being too focused on increasing cart value can also hurt your shop. Be sure you’re promoting not just larger orders, but more orders. An increasing number of orders of increasing value is your ultimate goal.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Visits</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all traffic to your website)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Visits are a number game: the more people browsing your shop, the more likely you are to make a sale. Even when you don’t close a sale, your chances of converting that visitor one way or another, increase. <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/">Well-designed lead magnets</a> are a great way to engage your customers, even before they make the decision to purchase. However, a large number of visits can be attributed to “bots” scanning your website. The overstated number of visits can decrease other stats like conversion rates.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Conversion Rate</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of orders / sum of visitors)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Conversion rates give online merchants a good sense of how many visitors actually complete purchases. This metric is especially useful for merchants who are trying to optimize their website design. During A/B tests, conversion rates help merchants decide which final design should be used.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Net Profit Margin</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all revenue &#8211; sum of all expenses)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This statistic is one of the most important numbers online merchants should analyze. It clearly shows how much money your business has gained or lost. By filling in fields like wholesale price, bank charges and shipping fees, PrestaShop gives you an up-to-date estimation of your business’s financial standing.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Products and Sales</h2>
<p>At the bottom of your dashboard page, you’ll find the product and sales table. It’s a quick summary of the information provided on your stats tab. We’ll detail what information each of the following tabs provides and how you can leverage that information.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20665" alt="product_sales" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/product_sales.gif" width="835" height="437" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Recent Orders</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab shows you the most recent orders placed on your website. It also details who made the purchase, the order size, and even the number of items purchased in the order. You’ll have a good idea of how busy or not busy, the business is. When you’re managing a team, it’ll help you decide how you should organize the staff and their responsibilities.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Best Sellers</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab simply shows you which products have been selling the best over the specified period of time. It’s worth noting if a specific image color or product category gets the most sales. Consider staging your images to mirror your best sellers or even purchasing more products that fall within the most-popular category.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Most Viewed</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This section simply lists the products that have been viewed the most by customers. Make sure you configure your back office to present the right numbers. Once you know which product is the most popular, match it against your best sellers list. Ideally the products should be similar. After all customers are more likely to purchase a product they’ve seen than one that they have not. If items on your most viewed list did not make the best seller list, consider adjusting the price to get customers to convert. Also keep in mind that a product’s merchandising may also play a role in how it’s viewed. For example, is the product currently listed on the homepage?</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Top Searches</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This table lists the top searches from customers browsing your website. It’s key to understanding what your customers are looking for when they visit your website. First, try searching each of these terms yourself to ensure they produce accurate results. If the search terms aren’t necessarily what you’re used to, consider adding them as “tag” to help customers find the product. Here are <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-essential-tips-to-improving-your-on-site-search-engine/">4 essential tips to improving your on-site search</a>.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>If you’re already using your PrestaShop back office dashboard, which stats do you refer to the most? Want to take a live tour of our dashboard? Check out the <a href="http://demo.prestashop.com/en/?view=back">PrestaShop demo</a>, then launch your own free <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/create-your-online-store">PrestaShop store</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help boost your holiday sales!<br />
<span id="more-20645"></span><br />
The <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/12/wrappers-delight-a-brief-history-of-wrapping-paper/266599/" target="_blank">history of wrapping paper</a> spans the globe, from Japan, where furoshiki, reusable wrapping cloths have been used since the 17th century, to Victorian Britain where gifts were hidden with decorative paper, ribbons and lace. Wrapping gifts is a common practice around the world, and for online shops, it can easily be adopted to improve the customer experience and increase bottom lines. Customers purchasing gifts that will be shipped directly to the recipient appreciate the option. </p>
<p>Here are a few ways to make your gift wrapping options stand out. </p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">1) Personalized Note Card</h2>
<p>The first way to personalize an order is by including a card that shoppers can customize with a short message. Consider <a href="http://www.moo.com/us/products/greeting-cards.html" target="_blank">printing custom greeting cards</a> with your company’s logo and branding. Keep in mind that customers may celebrate different holidays than you do, so note card design should be festive but neutral. They’re simple to include in the order packing process because all you have to do is drop the card in the box!  Although you can choose to hand-write these notes, printing the text ensures readability and reduces errors.</p>
<p>This is a great option if this the is the first time you’ve thought about adding gift wrap. It’s relatively easy to implement  it doesn’t take too many supplies. To keep costs low, opt for a simple postcard without an envelope.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">2) Box with ribbon</h2>
<p>A box with a ribbon is a standard way to wrap a present. Just think of Tiffany’s iconic blue box and white bow <a href="http://www.tiffany.com/WorldOfTiffany/TiffanyStory/Legacy/BlueBox.aspx" target="_blank">Tiffany’s</a>. To include  this gift packing option, pick a box size that would fit a normal order. The order should fit snugly, so the gift doesn’t move around in transit. If your products come in a variety of sizes, consider having a few different boxes on hand. For a cute and custom design, <a href="http://us.selfpackaging.com/91-gift-boxes" target="_blank">PrestaShop store Self-Packaging</a> offers a large variety of gift packaging for all types of items.</p>
<p>Another key thing to consider is how you’ll add the gift wrap into your packing process. Consider pre-measuring the ribbon or dedicating one person to gift wrap so that your regular orders are processed consistently. Keep in mind that these gift boxes with a pretty bow should fit in your regular shipping box, making this option pricier to implement.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">3) Printed Gift Boxes</h2>
<p>Similar to a box with ribbon is a printed gift box, with one noteworthy difference: it doesn’t need to be shipped inside another box. <a href="http://www.uline.com/BL_5603/Apparel-Boxes" target="_blank">Uline offers a wide variety of pre-printed gift boxes</a>. This affordable option simplifies the packing process because all you have to do is replace the original box with the new decorated box. And just like with the note card, gift box design should be neutral to accommodate a wide variety of holidays.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">4) Decorative Mailers</h2>
<p>If repacking your order into boxes is out of your budget, you can opt to mail presents in prettily designed mailers. There are 2 types: <a href="http://www.scotchbrand.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/ScotchBrand/Scotch/Products/Catalog/~/Scotch-Plastic-Bubble-Mailer?N=4335+5584761+3294580325&amp;rt=rud" target="_blank">bubble mailers</a>, which are great for items easily damaged during transit, and self-sealing poly bags. Compared to the regular mailers, decorative mailers look more fun and festive. Mailers are even easier to use and implement than gift boxes and ribbons.</p>
<p>This same concept can also be applied to products shipped in large envelopes or sleeves. There are countless vendors that offer decorative versions of these shipping materials.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">5) Custom Tissue paper</h2>
<p>Another quick way to implement gift wrapping is to add <a href="http://www.uline.com/CustomStaticTissuePaper.htm" target="_blank">custom tissue paper</a>, which you can order in bulk and have customized with a color and your logo. You don’t have to make any changes to the shipping box; you’ll just slip some pretty tissue paper into your standard shipping box. If you want to upgrade the tissue paper, seal the tissue with a sticker that features your logo.</p>
<p>No matter which gift wrapping options you offer, it’s important to include a packing list &#8211; a document that details the order without listing prices. This makes it easy for the gift recipient to make exchanges or returns and for you to processes these orders.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Do you currently offering gift wrapping on your site? Tell us what worked best on your shop. Not yet offering gift wrapping? Share with us the options you’ll start offering. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Countdown to the holidays</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape for the 2015 holiday season.<br />
<span id="more-20632"></span><br />
You can choose to promote a sale during each of the holidays we mention below, or just the ones you personally celebrate. Either way, be sure you plan everything in advance so your sales smoothly and without a hitch!</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_september-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_september" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19342" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">September</h2>
<p><strong>Labor Day</strong> &#8211; (Sept 7th) Wrap up the summer season with a Labor Day Sale. This long weekend is the perfect opportunity to convert customers and clear out your summer inventory to make room in your warehouse for holiday shipments. </p>
<p><strong>Rosh Hashanah</strong> &#8211; (Sept 13th) This Jewish holiday celebrates a new year. Those who celebrate it often receive money rather than gifts, so consider offering gift cards for the occasion. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_october-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_october" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19341" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">October</h2>
<p><strong>Halloween</strong> &#8211; (Oct 31st) This eerie holiday may seem like it’s only for brave souls. However, merchants can also take advantage of Halloween, especially those that include costumes, candy and creepy decorations in their product catalogs. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_november-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_november" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19340" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">November</h2>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving</strong> &#8211; (Nov 26th) Turkey, gravy and sweet potato pie: nothing says Thanksgiving better than overindulging in food with those you hold dear. When all the food has settled and the football game is won, families get into the holiday spirit by decorating their homes for Christmas. </p>
<p><strong>Black Friday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 27th) A sale day that traditionally starts the morning of the Friday following Thanksgiving; however, as large retailers have become increasingly competitive, Black Friday sales have been starting earlier and earlier each year. <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/black-friday-store-hours-2014-2014-11" target="_blank">In 2014, some sales started as early as 5:00PM on Thanksgiving</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Small Business Saturday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 28th) Supported by the Small Business and Entrepreneurship Council, Small Business Saturday encourages people to #shopsmall. If you own a retail location, check out these four ways to prepare for <a href="https://www.sba.gov/blogs/5-ways-prepare-small-business-saturday" target="_blank">Small Business Saturday</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Cyber Monday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 30th) Cyber Monday is to online retailers what Black Friday is to brick and mortar retailers. Today is the day ecommerce websites display their best sales to get customers to buy gifts from them. Smaller retailers can choose to list a major Black Friday + Cyber Monday sale that runs throughout the entire weekend, or flash sales that encourage customers to shop at specific times. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_december-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_december" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19339" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">December</h2>
<p><strong>Hanukkah</strong> &#8211; (Dec 6th &#8211; Dec 14th) Although this is a religious holiday, today  it’s common to receive a either different gift on each or simply one large gift on the last day of this celebration. Gifts can range from the traditional items to unorthodox mainstream ones.  If you’re decorating your website, keep in mind that Hanukkah colors are blue and white.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas Day</strong> &#8211; (Dec 25th) For Christians and non-Christians alike, Christmas has evolved into a holiday that celebrates family. It’s a time for exchanging gifts among friends and family. </p>
<p><strong>New Year’s Eve</strong> &#8211; (Dec 31st) Every family welcomes the new year in its own way. Some throw parties that go on all night, while others prefer a quiet dinner with the family. New Year’s is not generally celebrated with gift giving but can be a great opportunity to promote products that celebrate a new beginning. </p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">Preparing for the holidays</h2>
<p>Now that you know which holidays you want to plan for, determine which types of sales you want to run. Select the products you want to feature. There are a couple common tactics such as seasonal goods, top sellers, gift-friendly products or even highest margin. </p>
<p>Once you’ve decided o n the products, it’s important to decide on how you want to promote them. For example, would you be using <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/">pop-ups or pop-ins to engage your customers</a>? Or would you send out <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/">email newsletters</a> to advertise your sale? Regardless of which method you select, be sure you have enough time to set up your back office. </p>
<p>Not sure what is the best option for your store? Contact any of our module advisors on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Addons.PrestaShop.com</a>.  Already a seasoned pro? Share your tips below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 15:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20605</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Being an entrepreneur is an exciting prospect for many people, but it’s also a high-risk occupation. We’ve come up a with a few questions to consider before you take the plunge and launch your own business. For a more in-depth idea of what goes into building a business, download our How to Write a Business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/">Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Being an entrepreneur is an exciting prospect for many people, but it’s also a high-risk occupation. We’ve come up a with a few questions to consider before you take the plunge and launch your own business. For a more in-depth idea of what goes into building a business, download our How to Write a Business Plan ebook.<br />
<span id="more-20605"></span></p>
<h2>1. Why do you want to start a business?</h2>
<p>If your answer to this question is “I hate my job,” “I hate my boss,” or “I need a change,” then you should reconsider starting a business. Those are all good reasons to look for a new job or consider a different career path, but not to take on the risk and responsibility associated with starting a business. If you’re answer is something more like “I’m an expert in my field, I’ve got an idea that solves a problem and I’ve done my research,” then you’re on the right track.</p>
<h2>2. Do you have a problem?</h2>
<p>You can’t have a business without a problem, specifically a consumer problem. Does your idea address a specific need? Whose? The fundamental questions of what your product or service does and for whom, will form the basis for your business. You can’t start a business based on a vague “idea” or “market.” You need to offer unique value to your customers. Make sure you know exactly what this is before you launch anything.</p>
<h2>3. Are you passionate?</h2>
<p>Building a company is a long term effort, a lifetime in some cases. The road is not always easy, and it’s your passion and motivation that will keep you searching for solutions and plugging away when the going gets tough. When you start your own business, you’re trading in your 9-5 job for a 24/7 occupation&#8211;and if you love what you do, you won’t feel like you’re working.</p>
<h2>4. Are you disciplined?</h2>
<p>There’s a romantic image of the entrepreneur toiling away late into the night, putting all her energy into building a successful business. The reality is, if you don’t make time for exercise, a healthy diet and most important of all, sleep, you can kiss your dreams of long-term success goodbye. Growing a company requires exceptional time-management skills. You’ll need them to get your business goals accomplished and ensure that you carve out time for the other things in your life, like, you know, your family, friends, sleeping in on the occasional Sunday morning&#8230;</p>
<h2>5. Do you know what you’re doing?</h2>
<p>Ever heard the saying, “Write what you know?” The same holds true for business. It’s hard to envision obstacles and solutions for overcoming them when you have no idea what you’re doing. It’s hard to convince investors to believe in you if you come across as a novice. And it’s difficult to stay motivated when you feel lost at every turn. Many successful entrepreneurs spend years accumulating experience in an industry or honing specific business skills before deciding to the cut the connection with the stability of the good ol’ 9 to 5.</p>
<h2>6. Have you done your research?</h2>
<p>It’s one thing to dream up a company in your head and quite another to build one in the real world. Second in importance only to having an idea that solves a real consumer problem, is market research and financial planning. How big is the market for your product(s)? Who are your competitors? What kind of financial investment will you have to make &#8211; are you able to make? Don’t let these questions extinguish the burning desire you have to start a company; they’re simply there to make sure you don’t burn out before you have a chance to succeed.</p>
<p>Whether you’re ready to quit your day job and join the ranks of PrestaShop’s entrepreneurial community or still trying to figure out if running a company is really your thing, our ebook How to Write a Business plan will get you asking the right questions.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a style="font-size: 30px" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-business-plan"><strong>Download it for free!</strong></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/">Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 13:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hagen Meischner]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20615</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Many online retailers believe that when selling goods in an EU country, they can simply apply the legislation of their own country, even if they are aware that, in principle, the law of the supply country applies. In simple terms, they believe that this somehow also includes Switzerland. However, it is not as simple as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/">What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many online retailers believe that when selling goods in an EU country, they can simply apply the legislation of their own country, even if they are aware that, in principle, the law of the supply country applies. In simple terms, they believe that this somehow also includes Switzerland. However, it is not as simple as that. While Brussels has simplified the rules for online trading within the EU by providing a host of guidelines, special national provisions which must be complied with still exist for France, Belgium and Great Britain, for example. And then there’s the legal situation in Switzerland, which is not an EU country and has its own specific legislation.</p>
<p><span id="more-20615"></span></p>
<p>In this post, we will start by explaining the legal situation in EU supply countries (Belgium, France and Great Britain), followed by the legal situation in Switzerland. For an online retailer, the most important aspects to consider are the provisions governing the conclusion of contracts, general terms and conditions, pricing law, warranty regulations and mandatory use of the national languages. The right to withdraw has been fully harmonized in EU countries and, therefore, does not need to be explained. The exception to this is, of course, Switzerland, where EU law does not apply.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">France</h2>
<p>France intervenes heavily in defining the contractual freedom of retailers, especially in terms of consumer protection.</p>
<p>In France, a product description in a retailer&#8217;s online shop must be viewed as a binding <strong>contractual offer</strong>. To give a practice example, a retailer is bound to honor even inaccurate price information. The mandatory information that online retailers must display in their online shops is harmonized throughout the EU. However, France goes a step further by requiring online retailers <strong>to inform</strong> consumers <strong>of the provisions of warranty law</strong> in their <strong>general terms and conditions</strong>. They may be fined should they fail to do so.</p>
<p>The provisions of <strong>pricing law</strong> are relatively strict. Hence, mandatory detailed rules apply to price discounts on sale items. The competition authorities may punish infringements with heavy fines.</p>
<p><strong>France’s consumer warranty law provisions</strong> are similar to the EU standard. However, from 2016, the burden of proof rule relating to the existence of a defect on reception of goods, which places the responsibility on online retailers, is due to be amended. Until now, EU directives considered that the defect already existed at the time the goods were received, if the defect arose within 6 months and was reported to the online retailer. From 2016, this period will be extended to 2 years.</p>
<p>This represents a significant problem for online retailers: when a defect is reported, they must prove within 6 months that the problem occurred after the customer received the goods, if they wish to defend themselves against consumer claims. This may prove very difficult, or even impossible, in certain cases. Added to that is France’s two-tier warranty law which stipulates that consumers are able to lodge claims on hidden defects. However, the buyer must always provide proof of a hidden defect. With the new law, the two-year warranty period only commences when the defect is discovered and not when the goods are delivered.</p>
<p>Finally, in France, <strong>the French language is mandatory to the creation of an online shop</strong> and infringements may be punished by fines. Furthermore, consumers may invoke the fact that they did not understand information e.g. relating to the right to cancel, if it is not written in French, which grants a one-year right to cancel.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Belgium</h2>
<p>Belgium is (at least from a French point of view) the little sister of France. Many Belgian rules concerning online trading are similar to those in France.</p>
<p>However, in Belgium, unlike in France, product descriptions in <strong>online shops are not seen as binding contractual offers</strong> for online retailers. Belgian law is relatively strict regarding the <strong>validity of</strong> online retailers&#8217; <strong>general terms and conditions</strong>. Online retailers must ensure that Belgian customers are only able to complete the ordering process once they have declared that they have read and accepted the general terms and conditions. Otherwise, the general terms and conditions do not apply to the purchase of goods.</p>
<p>The language issue is particularly important in Belgium. Belgium has three official languages, so online retailers should provide an &#8220;opt-in&#8221; clause for application of the general terms and conditions in French, Dutch and German. Retailers&#8217; mandatory information, which they must display on their websites, must be presented in a specific format in Belgium. Where there is no right to cancel, online retailers must insert the following statement in bold on their websites (in the three official languages): &#8220;The buyer does not have the right to withdraw from the sale/purchase&#8221;. If this information is not visible, buyers will be treated as if they have a right to withdraw.</p>
<p>The rules governing <strong>pricing law</strong>, particularly for sale items, are similar to those in France. In terms of <strong>price labeling</strong>, Belgian law specifically stipulates that shipping/delivery costs must be included in the price. The provisions of <strong>warranty law</strong> are similar to those in France. And of course using the official language is mandatory in Belgium, which becomes particularly complex given that there are three official languages (French, Dutch, German).</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Great Britain</h2>
<p>Great Britain is the antithesis of France, so to speak. British law has significantly less influence over the contractual freedom of online retailers. A retailer-friendly approach is adopted regarding the conclusion of contracts and the validity of general terms and conditions.</p>
<p>However, the situation is different when it comes to <strong>pricing law</strong> and <strong>warranty law</strong>.</p>
<p>Online retailers can offer price discounts, but only if they refer to a comparison price (the online retailer&#8217;s previous price, another retailer&#8217;s price, the recommended retail or manufacturer&#8217;s price). Special discounts for sale items and introductory prices should not apply for longer than a month.</p>
<p>The provisions of <strong>warranty law</strong> are similar to the EU standard. However, in British law, there is no difference between used and new goods. Consumer warranty claims are subject to a limitation period of 6 years (5 years in Scotland) following the receipt of goods.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Switzerland</h2>
<p>Switzerland is not an EU country and has its own contract law, which is more retailer-friendly. Specific characteristics apply to mandatory information, the right to cancel, pricing law, product liability law and import legislation.</p>
<p>Switzerland does not require any comprehensive <strong>pre-contractual information</strong> regarding the web presence of online retailers as is the case in Germany. However, in many respects, Switzerland has adopted EU standards, meaning that it is advisable to apply the usual EU standard information requirements when supplying goods to Switzerland. There is no <strong>right to cancel</strong> as there is in the EU.</p>
<p>Swiss <strong>price labeling</strong> law is very strict and complicated. In principle, the final price, including taxes and customs duties, must be shown. However, because of complicated Swiss customs law, this is barely possible without professional help.</p>
<p>In Switzerland, <strong>advertising with price discounts</strong> is subject to strict rules. Online retailers must display a comparison price, which they have previously applied or refer to a comparison price, which competitors have charged. In the case of a comparison price based on their own previous price, a 2-month discount period applies.</p>
<p>As far as <strong>product liability</strong> is concerned, online retailers can import goods which comply with EU guidelines from the EU into Switzerland. However, there are numerous exceptions, meaning that online retailers should seek professional advice. This applies specifically to product groups, which are subject to a <strong>Swiss import ban</strong> (including, for example, foodstuffs, precious metals and animal products). In this case too, professional advice is essential.</p>
<h4 style="color: #27a9c3">About the author:</h4>
<p>Max-Lion Keller is a lawyer and partner in the law firm IT-Recht in Munich, which specializes in the field of e-commerce law. IT-Recht already protects several thousand online shop operators with its dissuasion secured legal texts, meaning that it is the market leading law firm in terms of continuous support for online retailers.</p>
<p>In addition, as part of its cost-effective general terms &amp; conditions maintenance service, IT-Recht provides dissuasion secured legal texts for numerous domestic and foreign online platforms: <a href="http://www.it-recht-kanzlei.de/Service/rechtstexte_fuer_onlineshops.php" target="_blank">http://www.it-recht-kanzlei.de/Service/rechtstexte_fuer_onlineshops.php</a></p>
<p>To obtain more information on the implementation of the EU standard in Version 1.6.1 of PrestaShop, simply visit our corresponding <strong>Blog Article</strong> or download your free copy of <strong>PrestaShop</strong>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/">What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20590</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today our guest writer Leah Hamilton, at TermsFeed, is going to clarify a few important aspects of legal policies that ecommerce business owners need to be aware of. When setting up your ecommerce store, you’re most likely concerned about how you’re going to market and price your product, what your website and branding will look [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/">The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Today our guest writer Leah Hamilton,  at TermsFeed, is going to clarify a few important aspects of legal policies that ecommerce business owners need to be aware of.</em></p>
<p>When <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2014/09/05/3-steps-to-launch-your-first-ecommerce-website/" target="_blank">setting up your ecommerce store</a>, you’re most likely concerned about how you’re going to market and price your product, what your website and branding will look like, and setting up various kinds of software, such as shopping carts and payment processing.</p>
<p><span id="more-20590"></span></p>
<p>The <em>last</em> thing on your mind is probably legal policies, especially ones concerning problems or customer returns. But these policies are very important: setting up good warranties and a returns policy that’s in line with the law can save you a lot of strife once your shop is up and running.</p>
<p>In this post, I’m going to go through what these documents are, what they should cover, and how to make sure yours are in line with the law. This article is intended to provide general advice only. If you have any specific questions relating to your business, speak with a lawyer.</p>
<p>Now let’s begin! First, let’s take a look at warranties and returns policies, and then we’ll go through the key sections that need to appear in each.</p>
<h2>What are Warranties and Returns Policies?</h2>
<h4>Warranties</h4>
<p>At its most basic, a <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/w/warranty.asp" target="_blank">warranty is a promise</a> you make about a particular item, such as how long it will last or what condition it will be in when you receive it. Warranties fall into two categories: express and implied.</p>
<p><strong>Express warranties</strong> are used around the world to explicitly promise how goods will perform and their condition. In an express warranty, you might tell your customers that you will repair or replace an item if it breaks within 1 year of sale. Or you might guarantee that the baby carriers you sell can hold up to 20kg. These are both examples of express warranties. If your customer relies on this statement as part of their purchase, you are legally bound as the store owner to ensure that your products respect the warranty conditions.</p>
<p>In the US, all new goods come with two <strong>implied warranties</strong>: the warranty of merchantability (which promises that the goods are what they’re advertised to be); and the warranty of fitness for purpose, (which promises that the goods do what you said they would do). These implied warranties can be excluded by way of a disclaimer, such as:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“The seller undertakes no responsibility for the quality of goods except as otherwise provided in this contract.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Or …</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“The seller assumes no responsibility that goods will be fit for any particular purpose for which you may be buying these goods, except as otherwise provided in the contract.”</em></p>
<h4>Laws and Regulations on Warranties</h4>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnuson%E2%80%93Moss_Warranty_Act" target="_blank">Magnuson-Moss Warranty Act</a> requires store owners to include implied warranties if any other written warranty is offered. This means that if you make any express warranty that the goods will last for a particular period of time, or offer any repairs or refunds, you cannot disclaim the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for purpose. If you exclude the implied warranties and do not give provide any express warranties, you are not giving your customers much reason to trust you, and this may dissuade them from buying your products. “As is” warranties are not permitted in several states.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gov.uk/accepting-returns-and-giving-refunds" target="_blank">In the UK</a>, you must offer a full refund if an item is faulty, not as described or doesn’t do what it’s supposed to, and customers have up to 6 years to make a claim for an item they’ve purchased. However, <a href="http://www.thisismoney.co.uk/money/bills/article-1677034/Two-year-warranty-EU-law.html" target="_blank">the likelihood of the customer being able to get that type of refund dramatically reduces 6 months after they’ve purchased the item</a>: past the initial 6 months, it falls on the buyer to prove that an item was faulty at time of purchase.</p>
<p>A customer has the same right to free repairs or a replacement whether they have a warranty or guarantee, or not. So you may still have to repair or replace goods if a customer’s warranty or guarantee has run out &#8211; or even if you didn’t give a warranty. It’s a good idea to define a clear policy outlining what warranties you offer and do not offer, and ensure that you comply with local laws.</p>
<h4>Returns Policy</h4>
<p>A returns policy might be combined with your warranties, or it might be a separate document. Usually the warranty sets out what is covered, while the returns policy simply defines how you will deal with customer returns and refunds.</p>
<p>The reasons for returns and exchanges are many and varied: a customer may not like the product, or perhaps the product arrived broken, or didn’t perform as advertised. If a product’s warranty is violated (e.g. you sold some spray deodorant cans but none of the sprayers worked, so they weren’t fit for purpose) US law requires that the warranty be honored with a repair or replacement.</p>
<p>Now let’s take a look at what you need to cover when you set up your warranties and returns policy.</p>
<h2>How to Draft a Warranty</h2>
<p>You should first ensure that your goods comply with the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for purpose. If you want to exclude these implied warranties, you can do so by using a disclaimer.</p>
<p>Your warranty should cover:</p>
<ul>
<li>What products are covered by the warranty and what products are not</li>
<li>The length of the warranty period</li>
<li>How you will respond if the goods are not fit for purpose or merchantable</li>
<li>Options for the customer to send or bring in the item for repair, replacement or refund</li>
</ul>
<p>You can offer longer-term or more comprehensive warranties as a way to build goodwill and show excellent customer service.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at an example from Apple.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_01.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple iPhone Warranty (<a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html" target="_blank">https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html</a>)</em></p>
<p>You can see that Apple puts consumer law considerations at the top of their warranty, so that the buyer is immediately informed that the warranty does not limit their rights under applicable laws. The warranty also clearly defines what is covered and what is not covered. Often customers are required to have met certain conditions before the warranty will be upheld. For example, you could require your customers to provide proof of purchase before you agree to provide warranty service.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of Apple’s terms where they also address customer responsibilities and what Apple will do if the warranty is breached:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_02.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple iPhone Warranty (<a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html" target="_blank">https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html</a>)</em></p>
<h2>What Your Returns Policy Should Cover</h2>
<p>Your Returns Policy will need to cover a number of things, such as time limits, amount that you are willing to refund (e.g. full purchase price), types of refunds (such as direct refund, store credit or replacement), and who covers the cost of delivery. Different jurisdictions have different laws on these issues &#8211; the UK differs from the US, and within the US laws differ state by state, and so on.</p>
<p>Your Returns Policy should cover both returns and refunds, and establish:</p>
<ul>
<li>Which items can be returned or refunded, and which can’t (e.g. digital downloads can’t be returned, but can be refunded)</li>
<li>Any time limits on returns or refunds (this will tie in to any warranty periods)</li>
<li>What form the refund will take (e.g. cash, exchange, store credit)</li>
<li>Who is responsible for the shipping cost of physical items</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s a visual example of the Apple Returns Policy:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_03.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple Store Returns Policy (<a href="http://www.apple.com/shop/help/returns_refund" target="_blank">http://www.apple.com/shop/help/returns_refund</a>)</em></p>
<p>Your policy should reflect the laws you are required to abide by in your jurisdiction. For instance, in the UK you must give your customer a refund if your product is broken or faulty, does not match the product description, or doesn’t do what it’s supposed to. So there’s no point writing a policy in the UK that says “No refunds for faulty products” when by law you are required to give a refund.</p>
<p>The UK also has “distance selling” laws that say you must provide a refund if the customer requests one <a href="https://www.gov.uk/accepting-returns-and-giving-refunds" target="_blank">within 14 days</a> of receiving the product, for any reason.</p>
<p>There are also laws that dictate how to display your policy.</p>
<p>For example, California law requires you to clearly display your return and refund policies unless you offer full cash refund, exchange or store credit, within seven days of the purchase date. If you don’t display your policy customers are allowed to return the goods for a full refund within 30 days, no matter what your policy says.</p>
<p>In Florida, you must clearly display your Return/Refund Policy if it does not allow refunds; if you don’t, customers may return goods for a full refund within 20 days of purchase.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Having good warranties and a returns and refunds policy for your ecommerce store is important for keeping your sales practices in line with the law. Ensure that you know your local legal obligations and display any policies and warranties prominently and clearly for your customers.</p>
<p>If you don’t currently have a Returns and Refunds Policy for your ecommerce store, <a href="https://termsfeed.com/return-refund-policy/generator/" target="_blank">visit TermsFeed to create one</a>. TermsFeed allows you to create custom legal agreements online, for your ecommerce website or app. The agreements are completely free, but TermsFeed also offers premium options if you wish to use them. TermsFeed’s agreements are drafted by professional lawyers from around the world, and each agreement goes through a rigorous quality certification process. Check out their <a href="https://termsfeed.com/" target="_blank">agreement generators</a> and <a href="https://termsfeed.com/reviews" target="_blank">testimonials</a>!</p>
<p>To add your Warranties and Returns and Refunds Policy to your footer, you’ll need to add CMS pages to your PrestaStore. Have a look at <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-complete-guide-to-create-cms-pages-for-your-online-store/">this handy guide</a> for how to do so.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/">The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back-to-School Basics: what every online merchant should know</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 07:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20585</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Fact: the back-to-school sales season is the second largest shopping season of the year. According to NRF, consumers spend an estimated $68 billion on back-to-school items. This represents a large conversion opportunity for online businesses of all sizes, as evidenced by the scores of similar statistics that populate back-to-school blog posts. If you’re a parent, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/">Back-to-School Basics: what every online merchant should know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fact: the back-to-school sales season is the second largest shopping season of the year. <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/NationalRetailFederation/backtoschool-2015-cheat-sheet?ref=https://nrf.com/resources/back-school-headquarters" target="_blank">According to NRF, consumers spend an estimated $68 billion</a> on back-to-school items. This represents a large conversion opportunity for online businesses of all sizes, as evidenced by the scores of similar statistics that populate <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/infographic-back-to-school-shopping-and-ecommerce-2014-2/">back-to-school blog posts</a>.</p>
<p>If you’re a parent, you’ve no doubt felt the season’s success lighten your pocketbook&#8230; If you’re not a parent, you’ve probably still taken advantage of the season’s unbeatable deals. In today’s post, we’re giving some back-to-school basics everyone can use to prepare for this late-summer sales event.</p>
<p><span id="more-20585"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #38acc5;">Who are Back-to-School Customers?</h2>
<p>For many people, the words “back-to-school shopping” conjure up memories of picking out the perfect set of crayons, pencils and paper. But this sales season has more to offer than grade-school writing supplies.</p>
<p>With an increasing number of adults pursuing higher education, customers shopping the back-to-school season have increased. <a href="http://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=372" target="_blank">In 2014, 21.0 million students</a> were expected to attend an institution of higher education. That’s a large number of new potential customers for online merchants to target.</p>
<h2 style="color: #38acc5;">What are customers buying?</h2>
<p>As the kind of potential customers shopping during this period has diversified, so has the variety of products purchased, the most popular being:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Office Supplies</strong> &#8211; These are the basic office tools students need: pens, pencils, paper, notebooks, etc. This list probably resembles what you bought as a kid &#8211; just with more options and cooler designs.</li>
<li><strong>Apparel</strong> &#8211; A new year, new you. Most families mark a new year of growth with new clothes, shoes and accessories. This is especially true for younger students who may have outgrown their clothes from the previous year.</li>
<li><strong>Books</strong> &#8211; A major portion of shoppers are looking for class-specific books. However, all types of book retailers can also promote volumes for younger students.</li>
<li><strong>Electronics</strong> &#8211; Obvious items include laptops, tablets and MP3 players. However, given that college students move out of their parents’ homes and into dormitories at this time, small household appliances also do well during this season. Think microwaves, coffee makers and mini-fridges.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/17452-gift-card.html" target="_blank">Gift Cards</a></strong> &#8211; These are growing increasingly popular among parents who pack their kids off to college.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #38acc5;">4 ways to convert shoppers</h2>
<p>The average student <a href="https://nrf.com/sites/default/files/Documents/BackToSchool2014 Final_0.pdf" target="_blank">spends approximately $650</a> during this shopping season, so it’s important to refine your marketing to convert more customers.</p>
<ol>
<li>There’s a lot to stock up on at this time of year, so everyone is looking for a good deal. Be sure your promote your sale 3-4 weeks before school shopping starts. Try sending out an <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/18921-official-mailchimp-for-prestashop-16.html" target="_blank">email newsletter</a> to announce the sale and drive traffic to your website. Pro tip: Try variations on Back-to-school to stand out from your competition. In the past, we’ve seen “Back-to-cool” and “Back-to-college.”</li>
<li>One of the fastest ways to convert shoppers is by offering <strong>free shipping</strong>. With slashed prices everywhere, free shipping reassures customers that they are getting a good deal by not having to pay shipping fees. Pro tip: Get customers to add more products to their cards by setting a minimum cart amount to qualify for free shipping.</li>
<li><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/19749-premium-flash-sale.html" target="_blank">Flash sales</a> is another great way to convince customers to check out. Display a countdown with the time remaining until the sale ends. This will incentivize customers to purchase immediately, rather than shop around at your competitors, and potentially miss out on your great deal.</li>
<li>Increase your <strong>average cart value</strong> by <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/11345-push-on-cart.html" target="_blank">suggesting products on your cart summary page</a>. Highlight products that didn’t make the traditional school shopping list, but would be fun to have. For example, products with character designs from this summer’s hottest movies.</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="color: #38acc5;">In a Nutshell</h4>
<p>The back-to-school period is the second largest shopping season. Not only are parents shopping for their children, adults pursuing higher education are also hitting the stores. They are specifically shopping for school supplies, apparel, books, electronics and gift cards to stores that carry these products. To convert shoppers, try sending email newsletters, offering free shipping, running flash sales or cross-selling in the cart.</p>
<p>Are you ready to tackle this back-to-school season? Share your tips and advice in the comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/">Back-to-School Basics: what every online merchant should know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 signs that PrestaShop is right for you</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-signs-prestashop-right/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-signs-prestashop-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 09:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20574</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Whether you’re looking to launch an online shop for the first time or thinking about migrating to a new solution, you may find yourself asking “Is PrestaShop right for me?” The fast and easy answer is “Of course &#8211; PrestaShop is right for everyone!” Making PrestaShop accessible and easy to use is how we envisioned [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-signs-prestashop-right/">5 signs that PrestaShop is right for you</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whether you’re looking to launch an online shop for the first time or thinking about migrating to a new solution, you may find yourself asking “Is PrestaShop right for me?” The fast and easy answer is “Of course &#8211; PrestaShop is right for everyone!”</p>
<p>Making PrestaShop accessible and easy to use is how we envisioned the software to be and something we work hard to achieve. However, having worked at PrestaShop for almost 2 years, I’ve learned that PrestaShop works better for some merchants than others. Today I’m sharing 5 signs that will help you decide if PrestaShop is right for you.<br />
<span id="more-20574"></span></p>
<h2>1. You’d like to sell products online.</h2>
<p>As a developer of ecommerce software, our main focus is helping online merchants sell their products. When we add features and functionality, we’re looking for ways to improve business for our online merchants. We work closely with our community &#8211; developers and merchants &#8211; so we get constant feedback about the new features they’d like to see added.</p>
<p>If you’re <strong>not</strong> going to sell products online, you can still take advantage of PrestaShop’s platform. Companies who want an online presence can easily cultivate one with our platform. It’s a great way to generate more buzz and excitement about your products, without having to manage the ecommerce side of the business just yet. Once you’re ready to start selling online, it’s simple to move from a showcase to a full-fledged store. Just check out this product catalog from <a href="http://www.jennifertaylorhome.com/" target="_blank">Jennifer Taylor Home</a> that was built using PrestaShop software.</p>
<h2>2. You’re cost-conscious or working on a limited budget.</h2>
<p>There’s nothing worse than having to fork over money before you even start selling products. Unfortunately, that’s the way business works. To help you limit your spending, we’ve made our software completely free. It’s not free for 30 days, or for your first 100 products. It’s just&#8230; free.</p>
<p>Even if you have the budget for a developer, our lightweight software and module-based environment make it easy for developers to create a custom shop quickly and easily. They can also use pre-made template themes to speed up development timelines. Both of these factors help decrease the number of development hours you need to invest in, saving you money.</p>
<h2>3. You like payment and shipping options.</h2>
<p>PrestaShop plays well with others. We work with other big names in the ecommerce industry, including shipping and payment solutions. By working together with industry partners, we can provide free modules that connect their services to your PrestaShop back office. Also, by working with multiple partners from the same industry, we give you plenty of options to choose from.</p>
<p>If you’re not sold on a particular service, our <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">merchant success team</a> is available to help you find the right solution for your business.</p>
<h2>4. You’re tech savvy.</h2>
<p>The best thing about using an open source platform is having full access to the software code. If you come from a technical background, you understand the freedom that gives you in terms of customization options &#8211; you can build your shop exactly as you see fit.</p>
<p>If you’re not too tech savvy, we’ve got you covered too. I’d recommend checking out our PrestaShop Cloud version. It’s the same great software we share with the community, just hosted for free. The only catch is that you have limited access to the source code, and you’re restricted to using modules that have been approved by PrestaShop Addons to limit risk to other shops we host.</p>
<h2>5. You’re looking to build and grow your business.</h2>
<p>If you need an online shop for a couple of days &#8211; maybe you’re thinking of doing a pop-up store &#8211; it may not be worth the time and effort to set up a complete online operation. The bulk of the features included in PrestaShop are targeted to merchants who want to build a business. Take for example, our analytics dashboard: at a glance, you can see your shop’s performance over the course of a week, a month, or even a year. Any math student can tell you that stats are only useful when compiled using data that’s been collected over a minimum period of time. </p>
<p>That’s just one of the many features built for serious merchants. Here are a few more:</p>
<ul>
<li>Different login for each team member, with their own set of permissions</li>
<li>Customer profiles and their order histories</li>
<li>Manufacturer and supplier management and analysis</li>
<li>Abandoned cart tracking to improve sales over time</li>
<li>Localization capabilities for increasing international sales</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s not to say that PrestaShop isn’t right for you if you’re running a small business. The easy- to-use back office makes setting up your shop a breeze. We won’t blame you for wanting to use PrestaShop, even for a few days. <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<h4>In a nutshell</h4>
<p>Just because PrestaShop is free, it doesn’t mean it’s perfect for everyone. The people who use PrestaShop most successfully are those who meet most of the following qualities:</p>
<ol>
<li>You’d like to sell products online.</li>
<li>You’re cost-conscious or working on a limited budget.</li>
<li>You like payment and shipping options.</li>
<li>You’re tech savvy.</li>
<li>You’re looking to build and grow your business.</li>
</ol>
<hr />
<p>Do these 5 signs point to you launching your shop with PrestaShop? If so, what are you waiting for? Create a PrestaShop account in seconds, then launch your own online business.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-signs-prestashop-right/">5 signs that PrestaShop is right for you</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-signs-prestashop-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Store audit &#8211; 100% Soccer</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/store-audit-100-soccer/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/store-audit-100-soccer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 07:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This week, we&#8217;re off to Spain! (&#8230;this one goes out to the PrestaShop soccer team!) We&#8217;re taking a play-by-play look at Futbolcienporcien.com, an online store from Madrid focused on customized soccer products. Navigation Strong points: The Futbolcienporcien logo very clearly indicates what their business is. The home page welcomes visitors into a clean, uncluttered store [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/store-audit-100-soccer/">Store audit &#8211; 100% Soccer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week, we&#8217;re off to Spain! (&#8230;this one goes out to the PrestaShop soccer team!)<br />
We&#8217;re taking a play-by-play look at <a href="http://www.futbolcienporcien.com" target="_blank">Futbolcienporcien.com</a>, an online store from Madrid focused on customized soccer products.<br />
<span id="more-20539"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">Navigation</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Strong points:</h4>
<p>The Futbolcienporcien logo very clearly indicates what their business is. The home page welcomes visitors into a clean, uncluttered store with high-quality images. It makes an excellent first impression!<br />
Additionally, the store is fully responsive and adapted to all web users. It&#8217;s great for mobile SEO.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>A highly visible search bar</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Currently the site&#8217;s search feature is only displayed when hovering over the magnifying glass.<br />
The search bar is an essential element of any online store carrying a large number of products, like this one does.<br />
Econsultancy.com released a study showing that 30% of visitors use a site&#8217;s search feature. The conversion rate of visitors who use search typically increases by 48%!</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">In addition to increasing your conversion rate, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/354-search" target="_blank">an effective search feature</a> gives you a great deal of information about what your visitors want. This can help you rework your keywords to optimize your search rankings, order the most-searched for products so you can meet expectations and improve customer satisfaction.</i></p>
<p>All data can be found in Google Analytics (Behavior / Site Search / Search Terms).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-analytics.png" /></p>
<p>You can look term by term to see how conversion rates improve for each word.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Very clear action buttons</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>When you hover over a product, you see 4 different icons: an eye, a magnifying glass with a &#8220;+&#8221;, and below the image, a heart and a double arrow.<br />
The problem with having just icons is that their purpose is not always clear. And that leads to a major problem—having to think while shopping, &#8220;What icon should I be clicking on?&#8221;</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-cta.png" /></p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">Make the icons in your store as clear as possible. You can add explanatory text, or guide your visitors with different colors depending on the actions you want to encourage.</i></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Site loading speed</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>As soon as you click on a product, the site takes several long seconds to pull up the page you&#8217;re waiting for. During my test – and this could of course change – page loading time was 4.57 seconds. There&#8217;s a major risk of losing visitors who were interested in your products, i.e. potential buyers.</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">57% of Internet users leave a website if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Out of those, 80% will never return. Optimizing your page load time makes it easier to convert visitors on your site and improve your organic search rankings!</i></p>
<p>You can use browser caching. To activate it, go to the <strong>Advanced Parameters / Performance tab</strong>:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/prestashop-performance-tab.png" /></p>
<p>There, you can configure all the tools: caching, combinations, compression, media servers, and more. For more advice, I also highly recommend that you check out <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Performance+Parameters" target="_blank">PrestaShop&#8217;s documentation for optimizing your online store&#8217;s performance.</a></p>
<p>Still not enough? <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/231-caching" target="_blank">There are several cache management modules</a> that will help you display your pages twice as quickly, and reduce the load on your server. Go right ahead: lots of e-merchants use these additional modules!</p>
<p>You might also want to optimize the size of your images. You can use <a href="https://imageoptim.com/" target="_blank">https://imageoptim.com/</a> for Mac and <a href="http://psydk.org/pngoptimizer" target="_blank">http://psydk.org/pngoptimizer</a> on Windows.</p>
<p>If the solutions above are not enough for your store, you can also contact your web host, who can advise you on the type of server that is best suited to your needs.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Readability</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Most of the text (category names, product titles, descriptions) is in all caps. Lowercase letters are far more legible. Web users don&#8217;t have to make an effort to read them (as they do with capital letters).</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;"><strong>Use lowercase letters for all your site content to make it easier to read</strong>, and if you must use capital letters, save them for a few action buttons. This will set them apart from the rest of the site.</i></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-readability.png" /></p>
<p>Additionally, the image is very clear in the example below, and it&#8217;s easy to see the sign-up field for the newsletter. However, the Twitter link and the RSS subscription link are hidden:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-brand.png" /></p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">When you use a background image, choose a <strong>color for your text and action buttons that is legible on every part of the image.</strong> Otherwise, use an image at less than 100% opacity (try 60% &#8211; 70%), with dark text.</i></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Cart: number of products or total?</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The cart is very clear and easy to access.<br />
However, it constantly displays the price to pay, even when collapsed.<br />
The same issue is present in the add-to-cart confirmation window:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-add-cart.png" /></p>
<p>Even the shipping cost is listed in this window. Seeing the total price and shipping fees could turn your customers away from finalizing their purchases. Let them browse through your different products stress-free!<br />
In this modal window, you can focus on additional one-click product suggestions to add to the cart, a feature offered in the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/modules-processus-de-commande/2412-cross-selling-on-cart.html" target="_blank">Cross Selling on Cart module</a>.</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">If possible, in the cart link and in the add-to-cart confirmation window, <strong>display only the number of products in the cart</strong>, and not the total purchase amount. This way, you can reassure your visitors without stressing them out about the overall amount. You can manage that step in the purchasing funnel.</i></p>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">Reassurance</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Strong points:</h4>
<p>The site has a very professional look. The tagline, &#8220;Expertos Futboleros desde 1999,&#8221; [Soccer Experts since 1999] is reassuring, especially with the date.<br />
The store&#8217;s address and phone number are also very reassuring.<br />
In the cart, the option for instant payment by PayPal also helps conversion rates.<br />
Finally, when ordering from Spain, there are two delivery options: one for customers in a hurry, and the other for those who want to save money.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>A reassuring footer</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The current footer shows the credit cards that (I imagine) are the ones accepted. However, the store&#8217;s selling points are not promoted. You should display them clearly, and add icons to make them more attractive!</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-reassuring-footer.png" /></p>
<p>What are some ways to reassure visitors? You could:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px; list-style-type: none;">
<li>- add a padlock with text saying &#8220;100% secure payment&#8221;</li>
<li>- say &#8220;Satisfaction guaranteed or your money back,&#8221; or &#8220;Customize your gear,&#8221; since that&#8217;s a service offered</li>
<li>- mention that customer service is available, and list store hours</li>
<li>- offer free shipping starting at a certain amount, or advertise &#8220;fast delivery&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Turn what you&#8217;re offering into advantages for your customers!</strong></p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;"><strong>Reassure your visitors</strong> to <strong>build their trust in your online store</strong>. To make this information visible on every page, it&#8217;s typically placed in the footer.<br />
You can make it <strong>highly visual</strong> using icons, trust seals, services that are recognized in your local market (payment and delivery), specific information (product return information, secure payment, etc.) and customer reviews.</i></p>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">SEO</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Strong points:</h4>
<p>The title tags and meta description on the homepage and product pages have been filled in.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>H1, H2 tags on the right elements</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Currently if you look at the source HTML of the home page or a product page, you can see that the H2 tags, in particular, are often placed around the price or number of articles in the cart.<br />
This problem can be fixed by going directly into the theme and putting H2 tags around the right elements. A front-end developer would know exactly how to help you with this.</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">By placing tags on the <strong>most important elements of each page</strong> (such as product name, brand, and subcategories), it&#8217;s easier to improve rankings for the content of your catalog.</i></p>
<p>Titles on all web pages must be surrounded by tags, from H1 to H6. H1 is the most important. These tags let you <strong>organize and rank the information on each page</strong> of your site.<br />
Imagine a book. H1 tags would be the chapter titles, H2 tags would be subtitles, H3 tags would be paragraph titles, and so on.<br />
These tags can help <strong>web crawlers read the page and improve your rankings</strong>, by indicating what the most important information is for each page in your store.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Content on product pages</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The product pages have relatively little text:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/futbol-product.png" /></p>
<p>You could add content, which would reassure your visitors and improve your search rankings.</p>
<p>For example, the same product on Amazon has much more text:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px; list-style-type: none;">
<li>- the team who played with this kind of ball (and the season when they played with it)</li>
<li>- the dimensions</li>
<li>- the outer material</li>
<li>- ball weight</li>
<li>- if the product is shipped inflated or not</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8230; and above all, the product&#8217;s selling points: how is it going to win over potential purchasers? Does it bounce better than other soccer balls? Is it more accurate, or pleasant to handle?</p>
<p><i style="color: #5b9bd5;">Each page of your e-commerce site is a chance to convince your visitors.<br />
Use 100% of each page. Make visitors want to choose your products by <strong>giving them as much information as possible and using an energetic tone</strong> that will win over future customers. This will improve your rankings and your conversion rate!</i></p>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">In closing&#8230;</h2>
<p>Your store offers high-quality products, great images, and is sure to interest soccer fans in other countries! Once you&#8217;ve optimized your store, you should translate it into English, offer international delivery, and list your products on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=google%20shopping" target="_blank">Google Shopping</a> to optimize your traffic and sales.<br />
Our whole team wishes you well on your journey!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/store-audit-100-soccer/">Store audit &#8211; 100% Soccer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/store-audit-100-soccer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join PrestaShop at our Miami MeetUp</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-miami-meetup/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-miami-meetup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 21:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20490</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you in the Miami area? Join the local PrestaShop team and other ecommerce enthusiasts at our Miami MeetUp! It’s the perfect opportunity to meet the local team, get sneak peeks from our latest software developments and even get a free website audit! Agencies, web developers, merchants, SEO/SEM specialists, freelancers and anyone who wants to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-miami-meetup/">Join PrestaShop at our Miami MeetUp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you in the Miami area? Join the local PrestaShop team and other ecommerce enthusiasts at our Miami MeetUp! It’s the perfect opportunity to meet the local team, get sneak peeks from our latest software developments and even get a free website audit!</p>
<p><span id="more-20490"></span></p>
<p><strong>Agencies, web developers, merchants, SEO/SEM specialists, freelancers and anyone who wants to sell online</strong>, come see how PrestaShop can help you grow your business. Any of our merchant success specialists can help you find the right tools to achieve your sales goals. Or come meet representatives from our partners to learn more about their products and services.<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/prestashop-miami-community-meetup-tickets-17928357199" target="_blank"> RSVP today on Eventbrite</a> for free tickets to this event. Complimentary food and drinks will be served.</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rubi Lounge<br />
</strong>141 Southwest 7th Street<br />
Miami, FL 33130</li>
<li>Tuesday, August 25, 2015<br />
6:00 PM to 9:30 PM (EDT)</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>Interested in getting a free website audit? Send an email with your shop URL to welcome@prestashop.com or reserve your spot! We’ll write you back to confirm your time slot.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><a class="btn get-me-started" style="color: #ea9629;text-decoration: underline;line-height: 26.6666679382324px" href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/prestashop-miami-community-meetup-tickets-17928357199" target="_blank">RSVP today</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Sponsored in part by:</strong></p>
<p><img class=" wp-image-20528 " alt="2015 Miami MeetUp Sponsors" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/meetUp-sponsors.jpg" width="560" height="81" /></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.3800000000000001;margin-top: 0pt;margin-bottom: 10pt"><span id="docs-internal-guid-ba048d5b-47d8-640f-3331-5ac6d433296e"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/simplifycommerce" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #1155cc;font-weight: bold;text-decoration: underline;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">Simplify Commerce by Mastercard</span></a><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent"> &#8211; An all-in-one payment solution from MasterCard. </span><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent"><br class="kix-line-break" /></span><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/management/avalara" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #1155cc;font-weight: bold;text-decoration: underline;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">Avalara</span></a><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent"> &#8211; A cloud-based service that handles all types of tax calculations for your online business. </span><a href="http://www.vinculumgroup.com/" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #1155cc;font-weight: bold;text-decoration: underline;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">Vinculum </span></a><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">- A SaaS-based product for multi-channel retailing. </span><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent"><br class="kix-line-break" /></span><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-hosting/a2-hosting" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #1155cc;font-weight: bold;text-decoration: underline;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">A2 Hosting </span></a><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;font-weight: bold;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">- </span><span style="font-size: 14.6666666666667px;font-family: Calibri;color: #000000;vertical-align: baseline;background-color: transparent">The preferred hosting solution for PrestaShop Download. </span></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-miami-meetup/">Join PrestaShop at our Miami MeetUp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-miami-meetup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
